[
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Dulari Devi from Bihar was awarded with Padma shri, she is associated with",
        "answer": "Madhubani Art",
        "choices": [
            "Madhubani Art",
            "Sikki Craft",
            "Mithila Art",
            "Patna Kalam"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "ICC Women Under-19 Cricket World Cup 2025 was held in ",
        "answer": "Malaysia",
        "choices": [
            "Malaysia",
            "India",
            "Australia",
            "Afghanistan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country won ICC Women Under-19 Circket World Cup 2025",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "South Africa",
            "Australia",
            "Pakistan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which Indian state became first to enact Uniform Civil Code",
        "answer": "Uttrakhand",
        "choices": [
            "Uttrakhand",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Maharashtra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Deepseek is related with",
        "answer": "Artifical Intelligence",
        "choices": [
            "Artifical Intelligence",
            "Quantum Computing",
            "Space Technology",
            "Defense Technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Aero India 2025 was organised in which city",
        "answer": "Bengaluru",
        "choices": [
            "Bengaluru",
            "Mumbai",
            "Delhi",
            "Chennai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Rekha Gupta newly elected Chief Minister of Delhi has won from which assembly seat",
        "answer": "Shalimar Bagh",
        "choices": [
            "Shalimar Bagh",
            "New Delhi",
            "Kalkaji",
            "Moti Nagar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which state Jaitapur Nuclear Power Project (JNPP) is proposed to be built",
        "answer": "Maharastra",
        "choices": [
            "Maharastra",
            "Karnataka",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Gujarat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "AI Action Summit 2025 was held in which country",
        "answer": "France",
        "choices": [
            "France",
            "USA",
            "India",
            "UK"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country would host next AI Action Summit",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "France",
            "USA",
            "UK"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who was the host for ICC Champions Trophy 2025",
        "answer": "Pakistan",
        "choices": [
            "Pakistan",
            "India",
            "Australia",
            "New Zealand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In Guillian Barre's Syndrome (GBS), immune system attacks it's own",
        "answer": "Nerve Cells",
        "choices": [
            "Nerve Cells",
            "Muscle Cells",
            "Brain Cells",
            "Blood Cells"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Quantum Computer Chip developed by Microsoft",
        "answer": "Majorana 1",
        "choices": [
            "Majorana 1",
            "Willow",
            "Lucy",
            "Maxwell"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Quantum Computer Chip developed by Google",
        "answer": "Willow",
        "choices": [
            "Willow",
            "Majorana1",
            "Lucy",
            "Maxwell"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Panchayat Devolution Index prepared by IIPA considers how many dimensons",
        "answer": 6,
        "choices": [
            6,
            5,
            7,
            4
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which state tops the Panchayat Devolution Index this year",
        "answer": "Karnataka",
        "choices": [
            "Karnataka",
            "Bihar",
            "Kerala",
            "Tamil Nadu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "A folk dance of Assam Tea Tribe and Adivasi Communities of Assam",
        "answer": "Jhumoir / Jhumur",
        "choices": [
            "Jhumoir / Jhumur",
            "Bihu",
            "Bhortal",
            "Bardo Chham"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name of new space telescope being developed by NASA for mapping universe",
        "answer": "SPHEREx",
        "choices": [
            "SPHEREx",
            "James Webb Space Telescope",
            "Wide Field Infrared Survey Explorer",
            "Euclid"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "SPHEREx is designed to create map of entire sky in how many different colour bands",
        "answer": 102,
        "choices": [
            102,
            101,
            100,
            103
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "SPHEREx will operate in which frequency range of light",
        "answer": "Visible & Infrared",
        "choices": [
            "Visible & Infrared",
            "Visible & Ultraviolet",
            "Ultraviolet & Infrared",
            "Visible & Xray"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The first woman to become the president of European Commission",
        "answer": "Ursula von der Leyen",
        "choices": [
            "Ursula von der Leyen",
            "Teresa Ribera",
            "Henna Virkkunen",
            "Kaja Kallas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the gas which leaked in Bhopal Gas Tragedy",
        "answer": "Methyl Isocynate",
        "choices": [
            "Methyl Isocynate",
            "Ethyl Isocynate",
            "Propyl Isocynate",
            "Butyl Iscoynate"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who is referred as Parrot of India / Tuti-e-Hind",
        "answer": "Amir Khusaro",
        "choices": [
            "Amir Khusaro",
            "Rumi",
            "Kabir",
            "Rahim"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The academy (Oscar) Best picture award went to",
        "answer": "Anora",
        "choices": [
            "Anora",
            "The Brutalist",
            "A Real Pain",
            "Conclave"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is the largest olive ridely mass nesting site present in the world",
        "answer": "Odisha",
        "choices": [
            "Odisha",
            "Mexico",
            "Costa Rica",
            "Bahamas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Olive ridely is related with which wildlife",
        "answer": "Turtle",
        "choices": [
            "Turtle",
            "Dolphins",
            "Penguins",
            "Eagle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Total population of Dolphins found in India according to recently relased Dolphin Survey Report",
        "answer": 6327,
        "choices": [
            6327,
            6732,
            6237,
            6732
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Total population of Dolphins found in Bihar according to recently relased Dolphin Survey Report",
        "answer": 2220,
        "choices": [
            2220,
            3330,
            1110,
            4440
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Flex Fuel is a mixture of ",
        "answer": "Petrol & Ethanol",
        "choices": [
            "Petrol & Ethanol",
            "Petrol & Diesel",
            "Ethanol & Diesel",
            "Petrol & Methanol"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is Vantara, the wildlife rescue, re-habilitation and conservation centre located",
        "answer": "Jamnagar",
        "choices": [
            "Jamnagar",
            "Gandhinagar",
            "Dholavira",
            "Ahmedabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the latest NASA mission to study corona of the Sun",
        "answer": "PUNCH",
        "choices": [
            "PUNCH",
            "Aditya L1",
            "Proba-3",
            "Helios"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Cryogenic temperature generally starts below",
        "answer": "minus 150 deg C",
        "choices": [
            "minus 150 deg C",
            "minus 273 deg C",
            "minus 123 deg C",
            "minus 100 deg C"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The fuel and oxidiser combination used in Cryogenic Engines are",
        "answer": "Liquid Hydrogen (LH2) & Liquid Oxygen (LOX)",
        "choices": [
            "Liquid Hydrogen (LH2) & Liquid Oxygen (LOX)",
            "Refined Kerosene (RP-1) & Liquid Oxygen (LOX)",
            "Refined Kerosene (RP-1) & Liquid Hydrogen (LH2)",
            "Liquid Hydrogen (LH2) & Liquid Nitrogen (LN2)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The fuel and oxidiser combination used in Semi-Cryogenic Engines are",
        "answer": "Refined Kerosene (RP-1) & Liquid Oxygen (LOX)",
        "choices": [
            "Refined Kerosene (RP-1) & Liquid Oxygen (LOX)",
            "Liquid Hydrogen (LH2) & Liquid Oxygen (LOX)",
            "Refined Kerosene (RP-1) & Liquid Hydrogen (LH2)",
            "Liquid Hydrogen (LH2) & Liquid Nitrogen (LN2)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "T-Cell used in CAR T-Cell Therapy is a type of which blood cell",
        "answer": "WBC",
        "choices": [
            "WBC",
            "RBC",
            "Platelets",
            "Plasma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What does CAR stands for in CAR T-Cell therapy",
        "answer": "Chimeric Antigen Receptors",
        "choices": [
            "Chimeric Antigen Receptors",
            "Chronic Allergic Reaction",
            "Chimeric Allergic Receptors",
            "Chronic Antigen Reactor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "First women president of International Olympics Committee",
        "answer": "Kirsty Conventry",
        "choices": [
            "Kirsty Conventry",
            "PT Usha",
            "Serena Williams",
            "Nadia Comaneci"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was the theme for this year Bihar Foundation Day",
        "answer": "Unnat Bihar Viksit Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Unnat Bihar Viksit Bihar",
            "Yuva Shakti Bihar ki Pragati",
            "Jal Jeevan Hariyali",
            "Nasha Mukt Bihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which city hosted SepakTakraw World Cup 2025",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Hyderabad",
            "Delhi",
            "Chennai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country topped the medal tally in Sepaktaraw World Cup 2025 hosted in Patna, Bihar",
        "answer": "Thailand",
        "choices": [
            "Thailand",
            "India",
            "Myanmar",
            "Indonesia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was India stand in medal tally in Sepaktaraw World Cup 2025",
        "answer": "4th",
        "choices": [
            "4th",
            "3rd",
            "2nd",
            "1st"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is the headquarter of International Sepaktaraw Federation (ISTAF) located?",
        "answer": "Bangkok. Thailand",
        "choices": [
            "Bangkok. Thailand",
            "Patna, Bihar",
            "Bali, Indonesia",
            "Kathmandu, Nepal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "BioE3 policy envisioned by Government of India stands for",
        "answer": "Biotechnology for Economy, Environment & Employment",
        "choices": [
            "Biotechnology for Economy, Environment & Employment",
            "Biotechnology for Economy, Environment & Energy",
            "Biotechnology for Electricity, Environment & Energy",
            "Biotechnology for Electricity, Employment & Energy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Mechi River is tributary of ",
        "answer": "Mahananda",
        "choices": [
            "Mahananda",
            "Kosi",
            "Son",
            "Ganga"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which Nuclear Fuel is most abundant in India",
        "answer": "Thorium",
        "choices": [
            "Thorium",
            "Uranium",
            "Plutonium",
            "Neptunium"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who formulated Three-Stage Indian Nuclear Power Programme",
        "answer": "Dr. Homi Bhabha",
        "choices": [
            "Dr. Homi Bhabha",
            "Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam",
            "Vikram Sarabhai",
            "C. V. Raman"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Three-Stage Indian Nuclear Power Programme is designed to utilise which natural resource of India",
        "answer": "Thorium",
        "choices": [
            "Thorium",
            "Uranium",
            "Plutonium",
            "Neptunium"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was the name of disaster and relief operation made by Indian Army for Earthquake hit Myanmar in 2025",
        "answer": "Operation Brahma",
        "choices": [
            "Operation Brahma",
            "Operation Buddha",
            "Operation Veer",
            "Operation Abhimanyu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was the 6th BIMSTEC Summit organised",
        "answer": "Thailand",
        "choices": [
            "Thailand",
            "Myanmar",
            "India",
            "Bangladesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country has the current chairmanship of BIMSTEC",
        "answer": "Thailand",
        "choices": [
            "Thailand",
            "Myanmar",
            "India",
            "Bangladesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many member countries are there in BIMSTEC",
        "answer": "Seven",
        "choices": [
            "Seven",
            "Six",
            "Eight",
            "Five"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is the permament secretariat of BIMSTEC located",
        "answer": "Dhaka",
        "choices": [
            "Dhaka",
            "Delhi",
            "Bangkok",
            "Kathmandu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The Waqf Ammendement Bill 2025 seeks to ammend which Act",
        "answer": "Waqf Act 1995",
        "choices": [
            "Waqf Act 1995",
            "Waqf Act 1905",
            "Waqf Act 2005",
            "Waqf Act 1885"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "India's first vertical Lift Sea Bridge",
        "answer": "Pamban Bridge",
        "choices": [
            "Pamban Bridge",
            "Chenab Bridge",
            "Atal Setu",
            "Sudarshan Setu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was theme of 76th Republic Day",
        "answer": "Swarnim Bharat: Virasat aur Vikas",
        "choices": [
            "Swarnim Bharat: Virasat aur Vikas",
            "Unnat Bharat Viksit Bharat",
            "Atmanirbhar Bharat",
            "Bharat: Loktantra ki Matruka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who received Padma Vibhushan this year from Bihar",
        "answer": "Sharda Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Sharda Sinha",
            "Sushil Kumar Modi",
            "Kishore Kunal",
            "Nirmala Devi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who received Padma Bhushan this year from Bihar",
        "answer": "Sushil Kumar Modi",
        "choices": [
            "Sushil Kumar Modi",
            "Sharda Sinha",
            "Kishore Kunal",
            "Nirmala Devi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the political leader popularly known as Jan Nayak",
        "answer": "Karpuri Thakur",
        "choices": [
            "Karpuri Thakur",
            "Jay Prakash Narayan",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Satyendra Prasad Sinha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which district Bihar's State Wushu Championship 2025 was held",
        "answer": "Muzaffarpur",
        "choices": [
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Patna",
            "Nalanda",
            "Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was Buddhisht Festival 2025 organised",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "Patna",
            "Nalanda",
            "Muzaffarpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was 38th edition of National Games India 2025 organised",
        "answer": "Uttrakhand",
        "choices": [
            "Uttrakhand",
            "Delhi",
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was position of Bihar in 38th National Games India 2025",
        "answer": "29th",
        "choices": [
            "29th",
            "30th",
            "28th",
            "27th"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "After how many years Bihar won Gold in 38th National Games India",
        "answer": "25 years",
        "choices": [
            "25 years",
            "24 years",
            "23 years",
            "26 years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which sport did Bihar win Gold in 38th National Games India 2025",
        "answer": "Triple Women Lawn Ball",
        "choices": [
            "Triple Women Lawn Ball",
            "Swimming",
            "Shooting",
            "Athletics"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many medals did Bihar win in 38th National Games India 2025",
        "answer": 12,
        "choices": [
            12,
            11,
            10,
            13
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "World record in Javelin throw in Diamond League 2025 is set by",
        "answer": "Julian Weber",
        "choices": [
            "Julian Weber",
            "Neeraj Chopra",
            "Arshad Nadeem",
            "Jan Zelenzy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "When is National Panchayti Raj day celebrated",
        "answer": "24th April",
        "choices": [
            "24th April",
            "22nd March",
            "24th March",
            "22nd April"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which city this year Panchayati Raj Day celebration event organised",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Ahmedabad",
            "Mumbai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the panchayat in Bihar that got Rank3 in Climate Action Special Panchayat Award",
        "answer": "Motipur. Samastipur",
        "choices": [
            "Motipur. Samastipur",
            "Mohanpur, Darbhanga",
            "Maner. Patna",
            "Mairwa, Siwan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, which state has highest monthly per capita consumption expenditure",
        "answer": "Sikkim",
        "choices": [
            "Sikkim",
            "Chhattisgarh",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Gujarat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, which state has lowest monthly per capita consumption expenditure",
        "answer": "Chhattisgarh",
        "choices": [
            "Chhattisgarh",
            "Sikkim",
            "Bihar",
            "Jharkhand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, which Union Territory has highest monthly per capita consumption expenditure",
        "answer": "Chandigarh",
        "choices": [
            "Chandigarh",
            "Jammu & Kashmir",
            "Lakshadweep",
            "New Delhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, how much is the estimated rural monthly per capita consumption expenditure of the country in rupees",
        "answer": 4122,
        "choices": [
            4122,
            6996,
            4927,
            13425
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, how much is the estimated urban monthly per capita consumption expenditure of the country in rupees",
        "answer": 6996,
        "choices": [
            6996,
            4122,
            4927,
            13425
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, how much is the Urban Non-Food expenditure compared to total MPCE",
        "answer": "60 pecent",
        "choices": [
            "60 pecent",
            "40 percent",
            "30 percent",
            "70 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Household Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24, how much is the Rural Non-Food expenditure compared to total MPCE",
        "answer": "53 percent",
        "choices": [
            "53 percent",
            "40 percent",
            "30 percent",
            "60 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the duration of National Critical Mineral Mission annouced in Budget 2024-25",
        "answer": "7 years",
        "choices": [
            "7 years",
            "6 years",
            "8 years",
            "5 years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the launch site used by ISRO recently for its 100th launch.",
        "answer": "Sriharikota",
        "choices": [
            "Sriharikota",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Thoothukudi",
            "Thumba"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is headquarter of ISRO located",
        "answer": "Bengaluru",
        "choices": [
            "Bengaluru",
            "Sriharikota",
            "Thoothukudi",
            "Thumba"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According Payment Systems Report published by Reserve Bank of India, which country tops in global remittances",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "USA",
            "China",
            "UK"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According Payment Systems Report published by Reserve Bank of India, which payment mode is most preferred in the country",
        "answer": "UPI",
        "choices": [
            "UPI",
            "Netbanking",
            "Cash",
            "Cards"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According Payment Systems Report published by Reserve Bank of India, which remittance corridor is the most effective",
        "answer": "Malaysia-India",
        "choices": [
            "Malaysia-India",
            "UAE-India",
            "Kuwait-India",
            "Qatar-India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the multilateral international initiative recently joined by RBI to enable instant cross-border retail payments",
        "answer": "Project Nexus",
        "choices": [
            "Project Nexus",
            "Project UPI",
            "Project Rupee",
            "Project PayNow"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Fiscal Health Index 2025 published by Niti Ayog, which state is the top performer",
        "answer": "Odisha",
        "choices": [
            "Odisha",
            "Bihar",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Gujarat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Fiscal Health Index 2025 published by Niti Ayog, which state is the poorest performer",
        "answer": "Punjab",
        "choices": [
            "Punjab",
            "Bihar",
            "Kerala",
            "West Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Fiscal Health Index 2025 published by Niti Ayog, what is the rank of Bihar",
        "answer": "13th",
        "choices": [
            "13th",
            "12th",
            "11th",
            "14th"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "From which state evidences of Iron Furnaces has been found which pushes the date of onset of Iron Age in India to 3345 BCE",
        "answer": "Tamil Nadu",
        "choices": [
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Bihar",
            "Andhra Pradesh",
            "Maharashtra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How much is the country's target power generation capacity from non-fossil fuels by 2030",
        "answer": "500 GW",
        "choices": [
            "500 GW",
            "1500 GW",
            "1000 GW",
            "100 GW"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In India which renewable source of Energy is being used most for power generation",
        "answer": "Solar",
        "choices": [
            "Solar",
            "Wind",
            "Hydroelectric",
            "Nuclear"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "As of October 2024, how much does renewable energy-based electricity accounts for, compared to  country's total installed capacity",
        "answer": "46.3 percent",
        "choices": [
            "46.3 percent",
            "34.6 percent",
            "63.4 percent",
            "36.4 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country has recently withdrawal from Paris Agreement",
        "answer": "USA",
        "choices": [
            "USA",
            "Canada",
            "UK",
            "India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the agreed limit on global increase in temperature according to the Paris Agreement",
        "answer": "1.5 degree celcius",
        "choices": [
            "1.5 degree celcius",
            "1.0 degree celcius",
            "5.0 degree celcius",
            "3.0 degree celcius"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Recently India entered the elite group of nations capable of executing space docking operations, what was the name of the mission carried by ISRO",
        "answer": "SpaDex Mission",
        "choices": [
            "SpaDex Mission",
            "SpaDock Mission",
            "SatDex Mission",
            "SatDock Mission"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the river over which world's highest rail bridge is constructed",
        "answer": "Chenab River",
        "choices": [
            "Chenab River",
            "Ganga River",
            "Kosi River",
            "Godavari River"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the height of Chenab Rail Bridge from river bed",
        "answer": "359 m",
        "choices": [
            "359 m",
            "539 m",
            "395 m",
            "593 m"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which district of Jammu & Kashmir, Chenab Rail Bridge - the world's highest rail bridge is located",
        "answer": "Reasi",
        "choices": [
            "Reasi",
            "Baramulla",
            "Jammu",
            "Srinagar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the current President of South Korea",
        "answer": "Lee Jae-myung",
        "choices": [
            "Lee Jae-myung",
            "Kim Moon-Soo",
            "Lee Jun-Seok",
            "Yoon Suk-Yeol"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Ukraine drone strike on Russian airbases was part of ",
        "answer": "Operation Spider's Web",
        "choices": [
            "Operation Spider's Web",
            "Operation Sindoor",
            "Operation Night Owl",
            "Operation Elephant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which Team won IPL 2025 season",
        "answer": "RCB",
        "choices": [
            "RCB",
            "GT",
            "PBKS",
            "MI"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was IPL 2025 Final played",
        "answer": "Narendra Modi Stadium, Ahmedabad",
        "choices": [
            "Narendra Modi Stadium, Ahmedabad",
            "Sawai Mansingh Stadium, Jaipur",
            "Arun Jaitley Stadium, Delhi",
            "Wankhede Stadium, Mumbai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who kept the Orange Cap in IPL 2025",
        "answer": "Sai Sudarshan",
        "choices": [
            "Sai Sudarshan",
            "Virat Kohli",
            "Shreyas Iyer",
            "Shubham Gill"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who kept the Purple Cap in IPL 2025",
        "answer": "Prasidh Krishna",
        "choices": [
            "Prasidh Krishna",
            "Jasprit Bumrah",
            "Varun Chakarvarthy",
            "Bhubhneshwar Kumar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the military campaign launched by India after terroist attack in Phalgam",
        "answer": "Operation Sindoor",
        "choices": [
            "Operation Sindoor",
            "Operation Spider's Web",
            "Operation Elephant",
            "Operation Smiling Buddha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the current Prime Minister of Canada",
        "answer": "Mark Joseph Carney",
        "choices": [
            "Mark Joseph Carney",
            "Justin Trudeau",
            "Stephen Harper",
            "Paul Martin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is ICRISAT Centre of Excellence for South-South Cooperation in Agriculture (ISSCA) located",
        "answer": "Hyderabad",
        "choices": [
            "Hyderabad",
            "Delhi",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Chennai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is Mount Etna located, which showed recent volcanic activity",
        "answer": "Italy",
        "choices": [
            "Italy",
            "Hawaii",
            "Japan",
            "South America"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name Europe's largest active volcano",
        "answer": "Mount Etna",
        "choices": [
            "Mount Etna",
            "Mount Helena",
            "Mount Pico",
            "Mount Elbrus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who among following is NOT part of Selection Committee created for selecting Chief Election Commissioner and other two Election Commissioners",
        "answer": "Chief Justice of India",
        "choices": [
            "Chief Justice of India",
            "Prime Minister of India",
            "Union Minister",
            "Leader of Opposition"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which year Genome India project was launched",
        "answer": 2020,
        "choices": [
            2020,
            2025,
            2010,
            2015
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Genome sequencing of how many individuals has been completed recently under Genome India project",
        "answer": 10000,
        "choices": [
            10000,
            1000,
            100000,
            100
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which city topped Global Power City Index 2024",
        "answer": "London",
        "choices": [
            "London",
            "New York",
            "Dubai",
            "Mumbai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the only indian city that has featured in the Global Power City Index 2024",
        "answer": "Mumbai",
        "choices": [
            "Mumbai",
            "New Delhi",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Hyderabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the newly appointed chairman of Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)",
        "answer": "V Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "V Narayan",
            "S Somanath",
            "K Sivan",
            "A S Kiran Kumar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "28th Conference of Speakers and Presiding Officers of Parliaments of Commonwealth Countries (CSPOC) scheduled to be held in",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "UK",
            "Australia",
            "Canada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the ISRO's mission to stduy sun corona",
        "answer": "Aditya-L1",
        "choices": [
            "Aditya-L1",
            "Gaganyaan",
            "NISAR",
            "Artemis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the combined mission by ISRO and NASA for earth radio imaging, using dual frequency band",
        "answer": "NISAR",
        "choices": [
            "NISAR",
            "Artemis",
            "MAIA",
            "TSIS-2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Trade Promotion Council of India successfully organised the mega 8th edition of Indusfood 2025 on January 8-10, 2025 at",
        "answer": "Greater Noida",
        "choices": [
            "Greater Noida",
            "New Delhi",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Gurugram"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "8th edition of Indusfood 2025 was inaugurated by",
        "answer": "Chirag Paswan",
        "choices": [
            "Chirag Paswan",
            "Piyush Goyal",
            "Shivraj Singh Chouhan",
            "Jagat Prakash Nadda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country has the chairmanship of BRICS for year 2025",
        "answer": "Brazil",
        "choices": [
            "Brazil",
            "India",
            "Russia",
            "China"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the new member country to join BRICS in 2025",
        "answer": "Indonesia",
        "choices": [
            "Indonesia",
            "Saudi Arabia",
            "Egypt",
            "Iran"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the portal developed by Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) India having access to INTERPOL databases",
        "answer": "Bharatpol",
        "choices": [
            "Bharatpol",
            "Indiapol",
            "India International Police Database",
            "India-Interpol Database"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which year Production-Linked Incetive (PLI) scheme was launched in India",
        "answer": 2020,
        "choices": [
            2020,
            2010,
            2015,
            2025
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many sectors are covered under Production-Linked Incetive (PLI) scheme in India",
        "answer": "14 sectors",
        "choices": [
            "14 sectors",
            "15 sectors",
            "11 sectors",
            "10 sectors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the position of India in list of largest operational metro network in the world",
        "answer": "third largest",
        "choices": [
            "third largest",
            "first largest",
            "second largest",
            "fourth largest"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was 18th Pravasi Bhartiya Divas 2025 organised ",
        "answer": "Bhubneshwar, Odisha",
        "choices": [
            "Bhubneshwar, Odisha",
            "Indore, Madhya Pradesh",
            "Patna, Bihar",
            "Ahmedabad, Gujarat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the resolution of newly developed Bharat Forecast system by Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology, Pune",
        "answer": "6km x 6km",
        "choices": [
            "6km x 6km",
            "12km x 12km",
            "10km x 10km",
            "8km x 8km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who is known as the father of Cooperatives in India",
        "answer": "Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel",
        "choices": [
            "Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel",
            "Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Verghese Kurien",
            "Dara Nusserwanji Khurody"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is India's first Cooperative University - Tribhuvan Shahkari Univerity established",
        "answer": "Anand, Gujarat",
        "choices": [
            "Anand, Gujarat",
            "Kheda, Gujarat",
            "Mumbai, Maharashtra",
            "Surat, Gujarat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was Ahilyabai Holkar born",
        "answer": "Chondi, Maharashtra",
        "choices": [
            "Chondi, Maharashtra",
            "Indore, Madhya Pradesh",
            "Mumbai, Maharashtra",
            "Raigarh, Chhattisgarh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who rebuilt Kashi Vishwanath Temple in Varanasi and Vishnupad Temple in Gaya, Bihar",
        "answer": "Rani Ahilyabai Holkar",
        "choices": [
            "Rani Ahilyabai Holkar",
            "Rani Chennamma",
            "Rani Lakshmibai",
            "Rani Durgavati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "When was Ahilyabai holkar born",
        "answer": "31 May 1725",
        "choices": [
            "31 May 1725",
            "31 May 1825",
            "31 July 1825",
            "31 July 1725"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the Indian Astraunaut to be part of Axiom Mission 4 - a commercial human spaceflight mission to the Ineternational Space station",
        "answer": "Shubhanshu Shukla",
        "choices": [
            "Shubhanshu Shukla",
            "Rakesh Sharma",
            "Ravish Malhotra",
            "Prashanth Balakrishnan Nair"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the first Indian citizen to enter space",
        "answer": "Rakesh Sharma",
        "choices": [
            "Rakesh Sharma",
            "Shubhanshu Shukla",
            "Ravish Malhotra",
            "Prashanth Balakrishnan Nair"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name ISRO Human spaceflight mission",
        "answer": "Gaganyaan",
        "choices": [
            "Gaganyaan",
            "Aditya L1",
            "Axiom-4",
            "Chandrayaan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "When was Namami Gange - a flagship union government programme to rejuvenate Ganga and its tributaries launched",
        "answer": 2014,
        "choices": [
            2014,
            2025,
            2024,
            2015
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which year was Indus Water Treaty signed between India and Pakistan",
        "answer": 1960,
        "choices": [
            1960,
            1950,
            1947,
            1999
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The joint military exercise (Army) between India and Nepal is called",
        "answer": "Surya Kiran",
        "choices": [
            "Surya Kiran",
            "Nomadic Elephant",
            "Garuda",
            "Indra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The joint military exercise (Army) between India and Mongolia is called",
        "answer": "Nomadic Elephant",
        "choices": [
            "Nomadic Elephant",
            "Surya Kiran",
            "Garuda",
            "Indra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The joint military exercise (Airforce) between India and France is called",
        "answer": "Garuda",
        "choices": [
            "Garuda",
            "Nomadic Elephant",
            "Surya Kiran",
            "Indra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Rcently launched, Stumped - is the autobiography of",
        "answer": "Syed Kirmani",
        "choices": [
            "Syed Kirmani",
            "Ravi Shastri",
            "Sunil Gavaskar",
            "Anil Kumble"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the autography of Sachin Tendulkar",
        "answer": "Playing it my way",
        "choices": [
            "Playing it my way",
            "Star Gazing",
            "Stumped",
            "Wide Angle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "PM Modi has recently laid foundation of India's first Green Hydrogen Hub in",
        "answer": "Vishakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh",
        "choices": [
            "Vishakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh",
            "Surat, Gujarat",
            "Patna, Bihar",
            "Mumbai, Maharashtra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to UN - World Economic Situation and Prospects Report 2025, what is the expected economy growth of India",
        "answer": "6.9 percent",
        "choices": [
            "6.9 percent",
            "9.6 percent",
            "2.6 percent",
            "3.4 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is Sepahijala Wildlife Sanctuary located",
        "answer": "Tripura",
        "choices": [
            "Tripura",
            "Nagaland",
            "Manipur",
            "Meghalaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is International Kite Festival celebrated in 2025",
        "answer": "Ahemedabad, Gujarat",
        "choices": [
            "Ahemedabad, Gujarat",
            "Mumbai, Maharashtra",
            "Kolkata, West Bengal",
            "Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which Indian Cricket player has been inducted to ICC Hall of Fame in year 2025",
        "answer": "Mahender Singh Dhoni",
        "choices": [
            "Mahender Singh Dhoni",
            "Virendra Shewag",
            "Virat Kohli",
            "Rohit Sharma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "First gene-edited animal in India is",
        "answer": "Sheep",
        "choices": [
            "Sheep",
            "Rat",
            "Pig",
            "Monkey"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the technology used in gene editing",
        "answer": "CRISPR-CAS9",
        "choices": [
            "CRISPR-CAS9",
            "CHIP-SEQ",
            "DNA-Split",
            "Genome-X"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the micro-organism known for their survival ability in space",
        "answer": "Tardigrades - Water Bears",
        "choices": [
            "Tardigrades - Water Bears",
            "Sea Horse",
            "Octopus",
            "Coral"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name India's first deep-water Sea Port built to handle Ultra Large Container Vessels (ULCVs)",
        "answer": "Vizhinjam International Seaport",
        "choices": [
            "Vizhinjam International Seaport",
            "Haldia Dock Complex",
            "Chennai Port",
            "Visakhapatnam Port"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the world's largest container ship that recenlty docked on India's newly built Vizhimjam International Seaport",
        "answer": "MSC IRINA",
        "choices": [
            "MSC IRINA",
            "OOCL Spain",
            "Ever Alot",
            "HMM Oslo"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Inequality in consumption in a population is measured by ",
        "answer": "Gini Coefficient",
        "choices": [
            "Gini Coefficient",
            "Ruban Coefficient",
            "Pop Coefficient",
            "Equality Coefficient"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the revised International Poverty Line for Low income countries set by the world bank in 2025",
        "answer": "3 dollars per day",
        "choices": [
            "3 dollars per day",
            "2.5 dollars per day",
            "2 dollars per day",
            "3.5 dollars per day"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How much is the poverty rate in India according to revised International Poverty Line",
        "answer": "5.25 percent",
        "choices": [
            "5.25 percent",
            "3 percent",
            "2.35 percent",
            "2.55 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the proposed date of completion of next census in India",
        "answer": "March 1, 2027",
        "choices": [
            "March 1, 2027",
            "March 1, 2025",
            "March 1, 2026",
            "March 1, 2028"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Future Minerals Forum 2025 is organised in",
        "answer": "Riyadh, Saudi Arabia",
        "choices": [
            "Riyadh, Saudi Arabia",
            "Dubai, UAE",
            "Doha, Qatar",
            "Cairo, Egypt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "India is not part of ",
        "answer": "ASEAN",
        "choices": [
            "ASEAN",
            "SAARC",
            "BIMSTEC",
            "BRICS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the chief guest on India's Republic Day 2025 event",
        "answer": "Prabowo Subianto, Indonesia",
        "choices": [
            "Prabowo Subianto, Indonesia",
            "Emmanuel Macron, France",
            "Adel Fatteh-al Sisi, Egypt",
            "Joe Biden, USA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "When was Jal Jeevan Mission - Har Ghar Jal was launched",
        "answer": "15th August 2019",
        "choices": [
            "15th August 2019",
            "15th August 2020",
            "15th August 2024",
            "15th August 2021"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "85th All India Presiding Officers’ Conference (AIPOC) was held in",
        "answer": "Patna, Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Patna, Bihar",
            "New Delhi",
            "Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh",
            "Indore, Madhya Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many Indian cities have been recently accredited as Wetland Cities according to Ramsar Convention",
        "answer": "Two - Inodre & Udaipur",
        "choices": [
            "Two - Inodre & Udaipur",
            "Two - Darbhanga & Jaipur",
            "One - Darbhanga",
            "One - Udaipur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which country won ICC World Test Championship 2025",
        "answer": "South Africa",
        "choices": [
            "South Africa",
            "India",
            "Australia",
            "England"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "South African team recently won it's maiden ICC world Test Championship under captainship of",
        "answer": "Temba Bavuma",
        "choices": [
            "Temba Bavuma",
            "Aiden Markaram",
            "AB de Villiers",
            "Kagiso Rabada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who was awarded as Player of the Match in ICC World Test Championship Final",
        "answer": "Aiden Markaram",
        "choices": [
            "Aiden Markaram",
            "Temba Bavuma",
            "AB de Villiers",
            "Kagiso Rabada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Pataudi Trophy is related to which sport",
        "answer": "Cricket",
        "choices": [
            "Cricket",
            "Tennis",
            "Badminton",
            "Javelin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Recently England Cricket Board renamed bilateral test series between India and England to be Tendulkar-Andreson Trophy, what was it called earlier?",
        "answer": "Pataudi Trophy",
        "choices": [
            "Pataudi Trophy",
            "Anthony de Mello Trophy",
            "Richards-Botham trophy",
            "Wisden Trophy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the first female ADC to the President of India",
        "answer": "Yashasvi Solanki",
        "choices": [
            "Yashasvi Solanki",
            "Sofiya Qureshi",
            "Vyomika Singh",
            "Shaliza Dhami"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Census of India is conducted under which ministry",
        "answer": "Ministry of Home Affairs",
        "choices": [
            "Ministry of Home Affairs",
            "Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation",
            "Ministry of Law and Justice",
            "Ministry of Information and Broadcasting"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Bill to allow Assisted dying for terminally ill adults was recently passed in lower house of which country",
        "answer": "United Kingdom",
        "choices": [
            "United Kingdom",
            "United States of America",
            "India",
            "France"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which of the following country is not a signatory of Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty?",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "USA",
            "UK",
            "France"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which of the following country is a signatory of Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty?",
        "answer": "Iran",
        "choices": [
            "Iran",
            "Isreal",
            "Pakistan",
            "India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "When was Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty signed?",
        "answer": "1st July 1968",
        "choices": [
            "1st July 1968",
            "5th March 1970",
            "5th July 1968",
            "1st July 1970"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many alphanumeric digits is used in DIGIPIN",
        "answer": 10,
        "choices": [
            10,
            9,
            6,
            11
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the size of geographical division made for DIGIPIN",
        "answer": "4m x 4m",
        "choices": [
            "4m x 4m",
            "6m x 6m",
            "9m x 9m",
            "12m x 12m"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the rescue operation conducted by Government of India to bring back Indian nationals from war struck Iran?",
        "answer": "Operation Sindhu",
        "choices": [
            "Operation Sindhu",
            "Operation Kagar",
            "Operation Sindoor",
            "Operation Brahma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the military operation conducted by Indian security forces against Naxalite insurgents in the border areas between Chhattisgarh and Telangana",
        "answer": "Operation Kagar",
        "choices": [
            "Operation Kagar",
            "Operation Sindhu",
            "Operation Sindoor",
            "Operation Brahma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was the theme of this year International Yoga Day celebration?",
        "answer": "Yoga for One Earth, One Health",
        "choices": [
            "Yoga for One Earth, One Health",
            "Yoga for self and society",
            "Youga for Vashudhaiva Kutumbakama",
            "Yoga for well being"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "First state to roll out e-voting system for municipal and urban body polls in India",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Kerala"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Strait of Hormuz connects",
        "answer": "Persian Gulf & Gulf of Oman",
        "choices": [
            "Persian Gulf & Gulf of Oman",
            "Persian Gulf & Gulf of Aden",
            "Red Sea and Gulf of Aden",
            "Red Sea and Gulf of Oman"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is the proposed CIP-South Asia Regional Centre (CSARC) Potato research centre coming up",
        "answer": "Agra, Uttar Pradesh",
        "choices": [
            "Agra, Uttar Pradesh",
            "Patna, Bihar",
            "Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh",
            "Amritsar, Punjab"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The proposed CIP-South Asia Regional Centre will focus research and development of",
        "answer": "Potato & Sweet Potato",
        "choices": [
            "Potato & Sweet Potato",
            "Wheat",
            "Rice",
            "Sugarcane"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the revised total coastline of India",
        "answer": "11098.81 km",
        "choices": [
            "11098.81 km",
            "7516 km",
            "9069.52 km",
            "10042.61 km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which state of India has longest coastline",
        "answer": "Gujarat",
        "choices": [
            "Gujarat",
            "Andhra Pradesh",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Maharashtra"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the primary use of GLP-1 (Glucagon-Like Peptide-1) drug?",
        "answer": "Treatment of Diabetes and obesity",
        "choices": [
            "Treatment of Diabetes and obesity",
            "Treatment of Cancer",
            "Treatment of Tuberculosis",
            "Treatment of AIDS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which constitutional amendment the term socialist and secular were inserted into the preamble?",
        "answer": "42nd Amendment",
        "choices": [
            "42nd Amendment",
            "44th Amendment",
            "52nd Amendment",
            "62nd Amendment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "When was emergency declared in India?",
        "answer": "25th June 1975",
        "choices": [
            "25th June 1975",
            "25th June 1980",
            "25th June 1965",
            "25th June 1995"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who has the authority to proclaim an emergency under Article 352?",
        "answer": "President of India",
        "choices": [
            "President of India",
            "Prime Minister of India",
            "Chief Justice of India",
            "Parliament of India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who was president of India when emergency was declared in 1975?",
        "answer": "Fakhruddin Ali Ahmed",
        "choices": [
            "Fakhruddin Ali Ahmed",
            "Shankar Dayal Sharma",
            "Zakir Hussain",
            "V. V. Giri"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Under which Article of the Indian Constitution can a National Emergency be proclaimed?",
        "answer": "Article 352",
        "choices": [
            "Article 352",
            "Article 360",
            "Article 370",
            "Article 356"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which constitutional amendment replaced the term “internal disturbance” with “armed rebellion” in Article 352?",
        "answer": "44th Amendment",
        "choices": [
            "44th Amendment",
            "42nd Amendment",
            "52nd Amendment",
            "62nd Amendment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "For how many months India was placed under state of Emergency by Indira's Government?",
        "answer": "21 months",
        "choices": [
            "21 months",
            "20 months",
            "18 months",
            "24 months"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who is the 14th and current Dalai Lama?",
        "answer": "Tenzin Gyatso",
        "choices": [
            "Tenzin Gyatso",
            "Gedun Drupa",
            "Thubten Gyatso",
            "Trinley Gyatso"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the position of current Dalai Lama - Tenzin Gyatso",
        "answer": "14th",
        "choices": [
            "14th",
            "13th",
            "15th",
            "11th"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The 14th Dalai Lama, Tenzin Gyatso, fled to India in which year?",
        "answer": 1959,
        "choices": [
            1959,
            1962,
            1960,
            1958
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which mountain range Lake Mansarovar is located?",
        "answer": "Kailash",
        "choices": [
            "Kailash",
            "Himadri",
            "Pir Panjal",
            "Zaskar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Fourth of july is related to",
        "answer": "American Independence day",
        "choices": [
            "American Independence day",
            "American Republic Day",
            "Birth of Jesus Christ",
            "Christian Halloween"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "On which date 13 American colonies declared independence from Britain?",
        "answer": "4th July 1776",
        "choices": [
            "4th July 1776",
            "4th July 1786",
            "1st July 1786",
            "6th July 1776"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many American colonies signed the declaration of independence from Britain on 4th July 1776?",
        "answer": "Thirteen",
        "choices": [
            "Thirteen",
            "Eleven",
            "Twelve",
            "Ten"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the last Indian warship purchased from the foreign country recently?",
        "answer": "INS Tamal",
        "choices": [
            "INS Tamal",
            "INS Talwar",
            "INS Trishul",
            "INS Tarkash"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who is the Prime Minister of Trinidad & Tobago?",
        "answer": "Kemala Persad",
        "choices": [
            "Kemala Persad",
            "Christine Kangaloo",
            "Jagdeo Singh",
            "Wade Mark"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is the capital of Trinidad & Tobago?",
        "answer": "Port of Spain",
        "choices": [
            "Port of Spain",
            "Accra",
            "Buenos Aires",
            "Brasilia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where is the capital of Ghana?",
        "answer": "Accra",
        "choices": [
            "Accra",
            "Port of Spain",
            "Buenos Aires",
            "Brasilia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the condition of End-of-Life Vehicles",
        "answer": "Petrol vehicles over 15 years and Diesel vehicles over 10 years",
        "choices": [
            "Petrol vehicles over 15 years and Diesel vehicles over 10 years",
            "Petrol vehicles over 10 years and Diesel vehicles over 15 years",
            "Petrol vehicles over 15 years and Diesel vehicles over 20 years",
            "Petrol vehicles over 20 years and Diesel vehicles over 15 years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "On bank of which river Keezhadi Civilisation was based upon?",
        "answer": "Vaigai",
        "choices": [
            "Vaigai",
            "Indus",
            "Godavari",
            "Krishna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many countries are member of BRICS as of 2025?",
        "answer": "Ten",
        "choices": [
            "Ten",
            "Five",
            "Six",
            "Eight"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the Indain state which overtook TB Death Free initiative in 2022 showing promiment reduction in death rate of TB patients?",
        "answer": "Tamil Nadu",
        "choices": [
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Bihar",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Kerala"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the first woman director of Railway Protection Force in India?",
        "answer": "Sonali Mishra",
        "choices": [
            "Sonali Mishra",
            "Kiran Bedi",
            "Kanchan Chaudhary Bhattacharya",
            "Meera Borwankar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which technology underlies cryptocurrencies like Bitcoins and Stablecoins?",
        "answer": "Blockchain",
        "choices": [
            "Blockchain",
            "Cloud Computing",
            "Artificial Intelligence",
            "Quantum Computing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What are Stablecoins",
        "answer": "Cryptocurrencies backed by an asset",
        "choices": [
            "Cryptocurrencies backed by an asset",
            "Cyrptocurrencies not linked to any fiat money",
            "Cryptocurrencies independent of market",
            "Cryptocurrencies issued by private entity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which type of asset can back a fiat-collateralised Stablecoin?",
        "answer": "Indian Rupee",
        "choices": [
            "Indian Rupee",
            "Cryptocurrency",
            "Oil",
            "Gold"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many days does Shubhanshu Shukla spent in space during Axiom4 mission?",
        "answer": "20 days",
        "choices": [
            "20 days",
            "15 days",
            "18 days",
            "16 days"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How much is the contribution from Non-Fossil Fuel sources in country's total installed electric capacity?",
        "answer": "50.1 percent",
        "choices": [
            "50.1 percent",
            "49.9 percent",
            "37.8 percent",
            "30.4 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "How many UNESCO World Heritage sites are there in India as per July 2025?",
        "answer": 44,
        "choices": [
            44,
            45,
            43,
            40
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the latest addition in UNESCO World Heritage sites in India in July 2025?",
        "answer": "Military Landscape of Maratha Empire",
        "choices": [
            "Military Landscape of Maratha Empire",
            "Moidams – Mound-Burial System of the Ahom Dynasty",
            "Sacred Ensembles of the Hoysalas",
            "Dholavira: A Harappan City"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "According to Article 145(3) what is the minimum number of judges required to interprete the Constitution or hear any reference?",
        "answer": "Five",
        "choices": [
            "Five",
            "Four",
            "Ten",
            "Seven"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the maximum one-time incentive for first-time employees under the ELI scheme?",
        "answer": "15,000 rupees",
        "choices": [
            "15,000 rupees",
            "50,000 rupees",
            "20,000 rupees",
            "25,000 rupees"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which of the following countries is not part of E3 grouping?",
        "answer": "Switzerland",
        "choices": [
            "Switzerland",
            "Germany",
            "United Kingdom",
            "France"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Under which Article of the Indian Constitution can a Supreme Court judge be removed from office?",
        "answer": "Article 124(4)",
        "choices": [
            "Article 124(4)",
            "Article 142",
            "Article 370",
            "Article 356"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What are the grounds for initiating impeachment proceedings against a Supreme Court or High Court judge in India?",
        "answer": "Proved misbehaviour or incapacity",
        "choices": [
            "Proved misbehaviour or incapacity",
            "Financial irregularities",
            "Treason",
            "Breach of privilege"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the minimum number of Lok Sabha members required to sign a motion for the removal of a judge?",
        "answer": 100,
        "choices": [
            100,
            50,
            150,
            200
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the minimum number of Rajya Shabha members required to sign a motion for the removal of a judge?",
        "answer": 50,
        "choices": [
            50,
            100,
            150,
            200
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "For a judge’s removal motion to pass in Parliament, what is the required majority in both Houses?",
        "answer": "Majority of total membership and two-third of members present and voting",
        "choices": [
            "Majority of total membership and two-third of members present and voting",
            "simple majority",
            "two-third of total membership",
            "three-fourth of total membership"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which Act regulates the detailed procedure for the investigation and removal of judges in India?",
        "answer": "Judges (Inquiry) Act, 1968",
        "choices": [
            "Judges (Inquiry) Act, 1968",
            "Judicial Review Act, 1970",
            "Indian Penal Code",
            "Representation of the People act"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The term of office of vice-president of India is mentioned under which article?",
        "answer": "Article 67",
        "choices": [
            "Article 67",
            "Article 124",
            "Article 56",
            "Article 65"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The title Gangaikonda Chola was acquired by which ruler?",
        "answer": "Rajendra Chola I",
        "choices": [
            "Rajendra Chola I",
            "Rajaraja Chola I",
            "Aditya Chola",
            "Kulothunga Chola I"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The Aadi Thiruvathirai Festival celebrates the birth anniversary of which great Chola emperor?",
        "answer": "Rajendra Chola I",
        "choices": [
            "Rajendra Chola I",
            "Rajaraja Chola I",
            "Karikala Chola",
            "Kulothunga Chola I"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the capital established by Rajendra Chola I?",
        "answer": "Gangaikonda Cholapuram",
        "choices": [
            "Gangaikonda Cholapuram",
            "Thanjavur",
            "Uraiyur",
            "Kaveripoompattinam"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the Pala king who was defeated by Rajendra Chola I?",
        "answer": "Mahipala I",
        "choices": [
            "Mahipala I",
            "Devapala",
            "Rajyapala",
            "Gopala I"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the first state in India to introduce an e-voting system for urban local body elections",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Kerala",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Karnataka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who has won the Sahitya Akademi Yuva Puraskar 2025 for Maithili language",
        "answer": "Neha Jha Mani for Benaras Aa Hum",
        "choices": [
            "Neha Jha Mani for Benaras Aa Hum",
            "Sushil Shukla for Ek Batey Bara",
            "Advait Kottary for Siddhartha",
            "Parvati Tirkey for Phir Ugna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who has won the Sahitya Akademi Bal Puraskar 2025 for Maithili language",
        "answer": "Munni Kamat for Chukka",
        "choices": [
            "Munni Kamat for Chukka",
            "Neha Jha Mani for Benaras Aa Hum",
            "Advait Kottary for Siddhartha",
            "Parvati Tirkey for Phir Ugna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "In which city has Chief Minister of Bihar recently inaugurated Bikram Lock Canal Bank solar power project",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Darbhanga",
            "Jamui"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What does NISAR stand for?",
        "answer": "NASA-ISRO Synthetic Aperture Radar",
        "choices": [
            "NASA-ISRO Synthetic Aperture Radar",
            "National Integrated Sattellite for Atmospheric Research",
            "New Indian Satellite for Advanced Remote Sensing",
            "National Indian Space Agency Radar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which launch vehicle was used to carry the NISAR satellite into orbit?",
        "answer": "GSLV-F16",
        "choices": [
            "GSLV-F16",
            "Falcon 9",
            "Araine 5",
            "PSLV-C50"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "NISAR employs a dual-frequency Synthtic Aperture Radar (SAR) system. Which two radar bands does it utilize?",
        "answer": "L-band and S-band",
        "choices": [
            "L-band and S-band",
            "Ku-band and Ka-band",
            "P-band and V-band",
            "X-band and C-band"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Among the two bands that NISAR utilises which one is provided by NASA?",
        "answer": "L-Band",
        "choices": [
            "L-Band",
            "S-Band",
            "X-Band",
            "C-Band"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Among the two bands that NISAR utilises which one is provided by ISRO?",
        "answer": "S-Band",
        "choices": [
            "S-Band",
            "L-Band",
            "X-Band",
            "C-Band"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What is the approximate revisit cycle of the NISAR satellite, meaning how often it scans nearly all of Earth's land and ice surfaces?",
        "answer": "Every 12 days",
        "choices": [
            "Every 12 days",
            "Every 6 months",
            "Once a year",
            "Every 24 hours"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which article of Constitution of India empowers the Election Commission to undertake the Special Intensive Revision (SIR) of electoral rolls in states like Bihar?",
        "answer": "Article 324",
        "choices": [
            "Article 324",
            "Article 423",
            "Article 234",
            "Article 342"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What was the magnitude of the recent earthquake that struck off Russia's eastern Kamchatka Peninsula?",
        "answer": 8.8,
        "choices": [
            8.8,
            9.5,
            9.1,
            8.2
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "The recent earthquake that struck off Russia's eastern Kamchatka Peninsula is part of which seismic active region?",
        "answer": "Circum-Pacific Belt or Ring of Fire",
        "choices": [
            "Circum-Pacific Belt or Ring of Fire",
            "Alpide Belt",
            "Mid-Atlantic Ridge",
            "San Andreas Fault Zone"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Shibu Soren was popularly known by which of the following nicknames?",
        "answer": "Dishom Guru",
        "choices": [
            "Dishom Guru",
            "Loknayak",
            "Netaji",
            "Janayak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who among the following is one of the founders of the Jharkhand Mukti Morcha?",
        "answer": "Shibu Shoren",
        "choices": [
            "Shibu Shoren",
            "Hemant Soren",
            "Jaipal Singh Munda",
            "Rajendra Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "On which date was Jharkhand officially formed as a separate state?",
        "answer": "15th November 2000",
        "choices": [
            "15th November 2000",
            "15th August 1999",
            "26th January 2001",
            "2nd October 2000"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Legislative Assemby of which state or UT in India has become completely solar-powered recently",
        "answer": "Delhi",
        "choices": [
            "Delhi",
            "Bihar",
            "Gujarat",
            "Lakshadweep"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which indigenous surface-to-air missile system was effective in a layered defense grid during Operation Sindoor?",
        "answer": "Akash",
        "choices": [
            "Akash",
            "BrahMos",
            "Prithvi",
            "Agni"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Name the latest release model of chatGPT",
        "answer": "GPT-5",
        "choices": [
            "GPT-5",
            "GPT-4",
            "chatGPT Agent",
            "GPT-4o"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "M.S. Swaminathan is best known for his contribution to which field?",
        "answer": "Green Revolution in India",
        "choices": [
            "Green Revolution in India",
            "Information Technology",
            "Space Science",
            "Indian Freedom Struggle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Who is known as the ‘Father of the Green Revolution in India’?",
        "answer": "M S Swaminathan",
        "choices": [
            "M S Swaminathan",
            "Norman Borlaug",
            "Verghese Kurien",
            "C Subramaniam"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Which National Sports Policy does NSP 2025 replace?",
        "answer": 2001,
        "choices": [
            2001,
            2010,
            2015,
            1992
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "Where was Asia Rugby Under-20 Sevens Championship hosted?",
        "answer": "Rajgir, Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Rajgir, Bihar",
            "Mumbai, Maharashtra",
            "Delhi",
            "Bhubaneswar, Odisha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "Recent2025",
        "question": "What percentage of seats does the Women’s Reservation Bill propose to reserve for women in Parliament and State Assemblies?",
        "answer": "33 percent",
        "choices": [
            "33 percent",
            "50 percent",
            "25 percent",
            "45 percent"
        ]
    }
]